Hello everyone, do you want to draw a draft on a virtual model and quickly preview the clothing outline?
In this update, we have launched a new 3D draft pen virtual model function, which will help you easily create a landing.
Using this tool, you can make free collage lines like painting on paper.
These drafts can not only instantly transform into 3D lines, but also directly generate 2D panels.
Next, let's explore this innovative and efficient workflow together.
We have prepared a virtual model in the 3D window in advance.
In the 3D tool bar on the left side of the screen, long press the 3D pen virtual model icon to change this menu.
Then, select the 3D draft pen virtual model tool added to the new one.
After selecting it, the upper left corner of the 2D window will pop up with the draft window.
Please note that the 3D window will not be opened.
Please note that the upper left corner of the 3D window will not be opened.
The 3D window will automatically switch to a front view that is optimized for drawing.
In this mode, the rotation function of the viewing angle will be limited to ensure the accuracy of the drawing.
But you can still freely place and balance the picture.
Now let's draw a draft on a virtual model directly.
Please make sure the type is set as a pen in the draft window.
Finally, you only need to press the mouse button on the model surface and drag it.
You can freely draw a line.
The system will carry out smooth processing in real time.
Ensure that the curve you draw is smooth and natural.
Next, I will introduce you to a few practical options in the draft window.
After the symmetry is used, the line draft is created along the center axis of the model center axis.
It is very suitable for the symmetry style such as making a jacket or a dress.
Switch to guide.
This function can actually preview the effect of the draft to be converted to a 3D curve.
The effect of the 3D curve is to bend the control point.
If the curve is not ideal, you can refer to the guide.
Directly check and adjust the position of the point.
3D view.
Press the button at the bottom.
You can quickly switch between the front and back view.
To effectively complete the outline of the entire clothing.
Let's use these functions in combination.
Let's draw a simple dress.
First, I will turn on the symmetry and conversion guide function.
Complete the front drawing.
Let's press the left mouse button.
Draw a smooth line according to the virtual model outline.
First, draw the front chest line.
Then draw the side seam line and waist line.
Next, draw the side seam line of the dress.
Then draw the side seam line of the dress.
And the line of the skirt outline.
Then switch to the back view.
Complete the back line draft.
When drawing the back, you can refer to the front line outline to draw.
Complete the front line outline.
If you draw it wrong, don't worry.
Just click on the line draft window.
The top of the front leather wipe icon.
And adjust the brush size between 10 to 100 pixels.
At this time, the mouse will become a double circle round light.
Drag directly on the line that needs to be modified.
Complete the wipe.
When drawing, press the Shift key.
You can easily draw straight lines.
And the wipe function will only wipe the lines of the current view.
After the draft is finished, you can convert it to actual usable data.
Click on the bottom of the window to convert it to 3D pen button.
At this time, your drawing is complete.
At this time, your 3D draft will be drawn in the form of a 3D curve at a moment.
Accurate projection.
And it is fitted on the model surface.
At the same time, the system will automatically switch to you.
Edit the 3D pen virtual model tool.
So you can adjust it immediately.
It is worth mentioning.
If you are drawing continuous lines from the front to the back.
After they are converted, they will automatically merge into a continuous 3D shape.
Finally, you just need to select these generated lines.
Use the flat flat as a panel tool.
You can create a 2D clothing version with seam-to-seam relationship with one button.
Today we have explored the new 3D line sketching virtual model function together.
No need for complicated data calculation,
Directly implement design on virtual models.
This is undoubtedly a once-in-a-lifetime workflow innovation.
I hope this function can help you.
With unprecedented speed and freedom,
Easily turn creativity into reality.
Let's take a look at the 3D model.